
NAME
    Get-Process
    
SYNOPSIS
    Gets the processes that are running on the local computer or a remote computer.
    
SYNTAX
    Get-Process [[-Name] <String[]>] [-ComputerName <String[]>] [-FileVersionInfo] [-Module] 
    [<CommonParameters>]
    
    Get-Process [-ComputerName <String[]>] [-FileVersionInfo] [-Module] -InputObject <Process[]> 
    [<CommonParameters>]
    
    Get-Process [-ComputerName <String[]>] [-FileVersionInfo] [-Module] -Id <Int32[]> 
    [<CommonParameters>]
    
    Get-Process -Id <Int32[]> -IncludeUserName [<CommonParameters>]
    
    Get-Process -IncludeUserName -InputObject <Process[]> [<CommonParameters>]
    
    Get-Process [[-Name] <String[]>] -IncludeUserName [<CommonParameters>]
    
    
DESCRIPTION
    The Get-Process cmdlet gets the processes on a local or remote computer.
    
    Without parameters, Get-Process gets all of the processes on the local computer. You can also 
    specify a particular process by process name or process ID (PID) or pass a process object through 
    the pipeline to Get-Process.
    
    By default, Get-Process returns a process object that has detailed information about the process 
    and supports methods that let you start and stop the process. You can also use the parameters of 
    Get-Process to get file version information for the program that runs in the process and to get the 
    modules that the process loaded.
    

PARAMETERS
    -ComputerName <String[]>
        Gets the processes running on the specified computers. The default is the local computer.
        
        Type the NetBIOS name, an IP address, or a fully qualified domain name of one or more 
        computers. To specify the local computer, type the computer name, a dot (.), or "localhost".
        
        This parameter does not rely on Windows PowerShell remoting. You can use the ComputerName 
        parameter of Get-Process even if your computer is not configured to run remote commands.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                Local computer
        Accept pipeline input?       True (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -FileVersionInfo [<SwitchParameter>]
        Gets the file version information for the program that runs in the process.
        
        On Windows Vista and later versions of Windows, you must open Windows PowerShell with the "Run 
        as administrator" option to use this parameter on processes that you do not own.
        
        You cannot use the FileVersionInfo and ComputerName parameters of the Get-Process cmdlet in the 
        same command. To get file version information for a process on a remote computer, use the 
        Invoke-Command cmdlet.
        
        Using this parameter is equivalent to getting the MainModule.FileVersionInfo property of each 
        process object. When you use this parameter, Get-Process returns a FileVersionInfo object 
        (System.Diagnostics.FileVersionInfo), not a process object. So, you cannot pipe the output of 
        the command to a cmdlet that expects a process object, such as Stop-Process.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Id <Int32[]>
        Specifies one or more processes by process ID (PID). To specify multiple IDs, use commas to 
        separate the IDs. To find the PID of a process, type "get-process".
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       True (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -IncludeUserName [<SwitchParameter>]
        Specifies that the UserName value of the Process object is returned with results of the command.
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -InputObject <Process[]>
        Specifies one or more process objects. Enter a variable that contains the objects, or type a 
        command or expression that gets the objects.
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       True (ByValue)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Module [<SwitchParameter>]
        Gets the modules that have been loaded by the processes.
        
        On Windows Vista and later versions of Windows, you must open Windows PowerShell with the "Run 
        as administrator" option to use this parameter on processes that you do not own.
        
        You cannot use the Module and ComputerName parameters of the Get-Process cmdlet in the same 
        command. To get the modules that have been loaded by a process on a remote computer, use the 
        Invoke-Command cmdlet.
        
        This parameter is equivalent to getting the Modules property of each process object. When you 
        use this parameter, Get-Process returns a ProcessModule object 
        (System.Diagnostics.ProcessModule), not a process object. So, you cannot pipe the output of the 
        command to a cmdlet that expects a process object, such as Stop-Process.
        
        When you use both the Module and FileVersionInfo parameters in the same command, Get-Process 
        returns a FileVersionInfo object with information about the file version of all modules.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Name <String[]>
        Specifies one or more processes by process name. You can type multiple process names (separated 
        by commas) and use wildcard characters. The parameter name ("Name") is optional.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    1
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       True (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  true
        
    <CommonParameters>
        This cmdlet supports the common parameters: Verbose, Debug,
        ErrorAction, ErrorVariable, WarningAction, WarningVariable,
        OutBuffer, PipelineVariable, and OutVariable. For more information, see 
        about_CommonParameters (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=113216). 
    
INPUTS
    System.Diagnostics.Process
        
        
    
        You can pipe a process object to Get-Process.
    
    
OUTPUTS
    System.Diagnostics.Process, System.Diagnotics.FileVersionInfo, System.Diagnostics.ProcessModule
        
        
    
        By default, Get-Process returns a System.Diagnostics.Process object. If you use the 
        FileVersionInfo parameter, it returns a System.Diagnotics.FileVersionInfo object.  If you use 
        the Module parameter (without the FileVersionInfo parameter), it returns a 
        System.Diagnostics.ProcessModule object.
    
    
NOTES
    
    
        You can also refer to Get-Process by its built-in aliases, "ps" and "gps". For more 
        information, see about_Aliases.
        On computers that are running a 64-bit version of Windows, the 64-bit version of Windows 
        PowerShell gets only 64-bit process modules and the 32-bit version of Windows PowerShell gets 
        only 32-bit process modules.
        You can use the properties and methods of the WMI Win32_Process object in Windows PowerShell. 
        For information, see T:Microsoft.PowerShell.Commands.Get-WmiObject and the Windows Management 
        Instrumentation (WMI) SDK.
        The default display of a process is a table that includes the following columns. For a 
        description of all of the properties of process objects, see "Process Properties" on MSDN at 
        http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=204482.
        
        -- Handles: The number of handles that the process has opened.
        
        -- NPM(K): The amount of non-paged memory that the process is using, in kilobytes.
        
        -- PM(K): The amount of pageable memory that the process is using, in kilobytes.
        
        -- WS(K): The size of the working set of the process, in kilobytes. The working set consists of 
        the pages of memory that were recently referenced by the process.
        
        -- VM(M): The amount of virtual memory that the process is using, in megabytes. Virtual memory 
        includes storage in the paging files on disk.
        
        -- CPU(s): The amount of processor time that the process has used on all processors, in seconds.
        
        -- ID: The process ID (PID) of the process.
        
        -- ProcessName: The name of the process.
        
        For explanations of the concepts related to processes, see the Glossary in Help and Support 
        Center and the Help for Task Manager.
        You can also use the built-in alternate views of the processes available with Format-Table, 
        such as "StartTime" and "Priority", and you can design your own views. For more information, 
        see T:Microsoft.PowerShell.Commands.Format-Table.
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 1 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>Get-Process
    
    
    This command gets a list of all of the running processes running on the local computer. For a 
    definition of each column, see the "Additional Notes" section of the Help topic for Get-Help.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 2 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>Get-Process winword, explorer | format-list *
    
    
    This command gets all available data about the Winword and Explorer processes on the computer. It 
    uses the Name parameter to specify the processes, but it omits the optional parameter name. The 
    pipeline operator (|) passes the data to the Format-List cmdlet, which displays all available 
    properties (*) of the Winword and Explorer process objects.
    
    You can also identify the processes by their process IDs. For example, "get-process -id 664, 2060".
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 3 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>get-process | where-object {$_.WorkingSet -gt 20000000}
    
    
    This command gets all processes that have a working set greater than 20 MB. It uses the Get-Process 
    cmdlet to get all running processes. The pipeline operator (|) passes the process objects to the 
    Where-Object cmdlet, which selects only the object with a value greater than 20,000,000 bytes for 
    the WorkingSet property.
    
    WorkingSet is one of many properties of process objects. To see all of the properties, type 
    "Get-Process | Get-Member". By default, the values of all amount properties are in bytes, even 
    though the default display lists them in kilobytes and megabytes.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 4 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>$a = get-processPS C:\>get-process -inputobject $a | format-table -view priority
    
    
    These  commands list the processes on the computer in groups based on their priority class. The 
    first command gets all the processes on the computer and then stores them in the $a variable.
    
    The second command uses the InputObject parameter to pass the process objects that are stored in 
    the $a variable to the Get-Process cmdlet. The pipeline operator passes the objects to the 
    Format-Table cmdlet, which formats the processes by using the Priority view. The Priority view, and 
    other views, are defined in the PS1XML format files in the Windows PowerShell home directory 
    ($pshome).
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 5 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>get-process powershell -computername S1, localhost | ft 
    @{Label="NPM(K)";Expression={[int]($_.NPM/1024)}}, @{Label="PM(K)";Expression={[int]($_.PM/1024)}},@
    {Label="WS(K)";Expression={[int]($_.WS/1024)}},@{Label="VM(M)";Expression={[int]($_.VM/1MB)}}, 
    @{Label="CPU(s)";Expression={if ($_.CPU -ne $()) { $_.CPU.ToString("N")}}}, Id, MachineName, 
    ProcessName -auto
    
    NPM(K) PM(K) WS(K) VM(M) CPU(s)   Id MachineName ProcessName
    ------ ----- ----- ----- ------   -- ----------- -----------
    6 23500 31340   142        1980 S1          powershell
    6 23500 31348   142        4016 S1          powershell
    27 54572 54520   576        4428 localhost   powershell
    
    
    This example provides a Format-Table (alias = ft) command that adds the MachineName property to the 
    standard Get-Process output display.
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 6 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>get-process powershell -fileversioninfo
    
    ProductVersion   FileVersion      FileName
    --------------   -----------      --------
    6.1.6713.1       6.1.6713.1 (f... C:\WINDOWS\system32\WindowsPowerShell\v1.0\powershell.exe
    
    
    This command uses the FileVersionInfo parameter to get the version information for the 
    PowerShell.exe file that is the main module for the PowerShell process.
    
    To run this command with processes that you do not own on Windows Vista and later versions of 
    Windows, you must open Windows PowerShell with the "Run as administrator" option.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 7 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>get-process sql* -module
    
    
    This command uses the Module parameter to get the modules that have been loaded by the process. 
    This command gets the modules for the processes that have names that begin with "sql".
    
    To run this command on Windows Vista (and later versions of Windows) with processes that you do not 
    own, you must start Windows PowerShell with the "Run as administrator" option.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 8 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>$p = get-wmiobject win32_process -filter "name='powershell.exe'"
    PS C:\>$p.getowner()
    
    __GENUS          : 2
    __CLASS          : __PARAMETERS
    __SUPERCLASS     :
    __DYNASTY        : __PARAMETERS
    __RELPATH        :
    __PROPERTY_COUNT : 3
    __DERIVATION     : {}
    __SERVER         :
    __NAMESPACE      :
    __PATH           :
    Domain           : DOMAIN01
    ReturnValue      : 0
    User             : user01
    
    
    This command shows how to find the owner of a process. Because the System.Diagnostics.Process 
    object that Get-Process returns does not have a property or method that returns the process owner, 
    the command uses
    
    the Get-WmiObject cmdlet to get a Win32_Process object that represents the same process.
    
    The first command uses Get-WmiObject to get the PowerShell process. It saves it in the $p variable.
    
    The second command uses the GetOwner method to get the owner of the process in $p. The command 
    reveals that the owner is Domain01\user01.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 9 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>get-process powershell
    
    Handles  NPM(K)    PM(K)      WS(K) VM(M)   CPU(s)     Id ProcessName
    -------  ------    -----      ----- -----   ------     -- -----------
    308      26    52308      61780   567     3.18   5632 powershell
    377      26    62676      63384   575     3.88   5888 powershellPS C:\>get-process -id $pid
    Handles  NPM(K)    PM(K)      WS(K) VM(M)   CPU(s)     Id ProcessName
    -------  ------    -----      ----- -----   ------     -- -----------
    396      26    56488      57236   575     3.90   5888 powershell
    
    
    These commands show how to use the $pid automatic variable to identify the process that is hosting 
    the current Windows PowerShell session. You can use this method to distinguish the host process 
    from other Windows PowerShell processes that you might want to stop or close. The first command 
    gets all of the Windows PowerShell processes in the current session.
    
    The second command gets the Windows PowerShell process that is hosting the current session.
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 10 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>get-process | where {$_.mainWindowTitle} | format-table id, name, mainwindowtitle -autosize
    
    
    This command gets all the processes that have a main window title, and it displays them in a table 
    with the process ID and the process name.
    
    The mainWindowTitle property is just one of many useful properties of the 
    System.Diagnostics.Process object that Get-Process returns. To view all of the properties, pipe the 
    results of a Get-Process command to the T:Microsoft.PowerShell.Commands.Get-Member cmdlet 
    (get-process | get-member).
    
    
    
    
    
    
RELATED LINKS
    Online Version: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=290498
    Debug-Process 
    Get-Process 
    Start-Process 
    Stop-Process 
    Wait-Process 



